[A Moment But Forever]
[Episode 24]
[Ningrui Pavilion]
♫I gaze into your deep eyes♫
♫For whom do you take apart the word "love"?♫
♫Turning around, it's like a dream♫
♫I have betrayed deep love♫
♫Heaving a long, helpless sigh♫
♫Time flies too rapidly♫
♫Life is like a flying bird♫
♫Joining, scattering, no way back♫
Stop being unreasonable.
♫Unable to get what I yearn for, I sink in sadness♫
I won't be nice to you if you keep messing with me.
You startled my horse and it broke away.
But you didn't even apologize.
♫When I brush past love fate is set♫
Tell me, don't you deserve a beating?
Your horse ran away on its own.
What does it have to do with me?
♫I've used up my brush and ink♫
I simply coughed and it was scared away.
Do you think it's safe to ride a horse of that kind?
♫I couldn't describe♫
Anyway, I demand compensation.
♫This lovesick path with you♫
This is ridiculous.
♫After the farewell, where are you now?♫
♫Who do you spend your days with?♫
♫Do you know I'm willing to wait for you until the end?♫
♫Sighing that the world is too lonely♫
♫They laugh at me for being foolish♫
You're no match for me.
You don't even dare to draw your sword out.
♫Longing is in my song; the people are not as before♫
Yet you have the audacity to bluff.
Fine, young lady,
if you must learn this lesson the hard way.
♫The wind is bound to miss♫
♫The thick clouds♫
Are you okay?
♫Fate leaves no room for regrets♫
You're a skillful martial fighter,
but not an experienced one.
♫Fate only urges you to move forward♫
Sir, since I left Yandu,
I've met many skillful fighters,
but you're the first one
that I find respectable.
♫Can't get what I yearn for, I sink in sadness♫
How about this?
If you have a rematch with me,
♫When I brush past love, fate is set♫
that little dispute of ours will be ended.
What do you say?
Let's have one more match with our bare hands.
♫I've used up my brush and ink♫
♫I couldn't describe♫
♫This lovesick path with you♫
♫After the farewell, where are you now?♫
♫Who do you spend your days with?♫
What are you looking at?
♫Do you know I'm willing to wait for you until the end?♫
Nothing.
Some memories just flooded back.
♫Sighing that the world is too lonely♫
Eat the soup now.
♫They laugh at me for being foolish♫
Zhi Dai...
♫Longing is in my song; the people are not as before♫
I'm sorry.
♫People are not as they were in this lifetime♫
You already woke up?
Did I...
Did I disturb you?
No.
Tanyin just brought some
food and supplies to you.
She thought you were asleep,
so she left.
I'll put them there then?
Do you want to meet her?
She probably hasn't gone far.
I can go get her back.
Lift up your head.
I've never noticed
how long your hair is.
Why don't I tie it up for you?
No need.
Come on.
Come on!
You hair is so stiff.
Flyaway, too.
Why don't I put your hair into braids?
No.
Come on,
you always reject me.
Don't you see
how good my skills are?
Be honest with me.
Does my hairstyle look bad to you?
No braids.
Fine, I won't put your hair into braids.
You're close with Tanyin, aren't you?
I saw clothes and boots
in the packages she sent you.
It means she even knows
your measurements.
She's a craftsman.
She has a keen eye.
She can also figure out
your measurements with just a glimpse at you.
Really?
That's impressive.
All done!
What do you think?
It seems pretty good to me.
It's much neater than before.
When you put some new clothes on,
you'll definitely look stunning.
Do you have a crush on Tanyin?
I'm a War Demon.
A War Demon
who is deprived of his magic source.
I lost my mother,
and caused my brother's death,
I'm homeless,
with my life at stake.
Who am I
to love anyone?
Miss Ji, Miss Ji!
Mr. Xu,
I told you I had something else to do.
Nothing is more important
than what I have for you here.
Listen,
just wait here for a moment.
Just a moment.
I'll bring someone to meet you.
Now is really late.
I must go.
Miss Ji,
why are you so stubborn?
I'm telling you,
a big shot
likes the Lucky Eggs you created.
You are so blessed.
This drawing shows how to make Lucky Eggs.
Please give it
to that big shot.
Tell him
that I thank him for appreciating my creation.
I have to be somewhere else now,
so I can't meet with him.
I'll be going now.
Miss J! Miss Ji!
I...
This...
Mr. Yuan,
waiting for your wife again, aren't you?
At this hour of the day,
I guess she's on her way back.
You'll have noodles as usual, right?
Yes.
Alright, two bowls of noodles.
Welcome.
Come on in.
What would you like to order?
Miss, a gentleman
asked me to give this to you.
He said this lantern
will lead you to him.
He would like a word with you.
Who is that gentleman?
Did he tell you
his name?
Could it be Yuanzhong?
Mr. Yuan,
it's my fault
for cooking the noodles too early.
How about this?
I'll take these away
now,
and bring you freshly cooked noodles
when your wife arrives.
Thank you.
No worries.
You stay put.
Miss, you arrived
sooner than I expected.
It's you.
What do you want from me?
Why not take a seat
for a nice chat with me?
Bravo! Bravo! Bravo!
One more!
Bravo!
Ma'am,
you'll look great with this on.
It does look good.
I'll take this.
I'd like to pick some more items as gifts.
You have great taste.
What are you doing here?
Beanie, are you okay?
This little boy looks strong and spirited.
What a good boy.
So adorable.
I bet he's blessed with good fortune.
Do you like this?
I have so many more of this at home.
Sir, why don't you bring the boy to my place
for a visit and a play date?
No need.
Have you seen Ji Tanyin?
[Subtle Fragrance and Lonely Shadows]
Why did you stop?
That was the end.
What do you think of it?
I don't know much about music.
Just tell me if it sounded good or not.
It was nice.
It sounded melancholy,
but joyful at the same time.
It was like someone spent several days and nights
creating something
to his satisfaction.
He felt exhausted
but meanwhile pleased.
You're amazing.
I've played this piece
for many people,
and received a lot of praise
and compliments.
However,
only your interpretation
speaks my mind.
Why on earth did you
lead me here?
Just to hear you play this piece?
Do you really not remember me?
Should I remember you?
This is truly heartbreaking.
I shouldn't have spent so many days and nights thinking about you.
Miss,
what do you think of me?
What do you mean?
How is my appearance?
How is my body shape?
Do you like
my demeanor and manner?
Mr. Fu.
If you keep talking nonsense like this,
I'll leave right away.
Highly improbable.
By all accounts,
I should be
the most ideal man you could imagine.
The High Priest of Youhu Clan
is not even half as good as me.
Why would you like him?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Or is the Divine Left Hand your real purpose?
Do you plan to take his hand away?
I can tell from his looks
that if he loses the Divine Left Hand,
he won't live long.
Who are you exactly?
Venture a guess.
Come on, take a guess.
Won't it be boring
if I just give you the answer?
High Priest, you have such a hot temper.
Miss Ji,
we had such a lovely chat.
Too bad that it was interrupted by an uninvited guest.
I'll talk to you next time.
Slow down, please!
Yuanzhong!
Have you eaten dinner yet?
I haven't.
Shall we go buy some
sweet cakes?
What about the noodles?
What noodles?
You want sweet cakes.
Fine. I'm okay with it.
But why
couldn't you tell me earlier?
I bought two bowls of noodles and I waited for you.
What should we do with the noodles now?
I...
At the exact time I knew you would be back,
I went to the restaurant, ordered two bowls of noodles,
and waited from day to night for you.
If I had known
that you wanted sweet cakes,
I wouldn't have gone to the trouble
of ordering two bowls of noodles, right?
Now the noodles are all mushy.
How can we eat it?
It's okay. I can have noodles.
Ji Tanyin.
How come I never noticed
what a fickle woman you are?
Didn't you
just ask for sweet cakes?
Why do you want to have noodles now?
It's too late.
Those two bowls of noodles
have already been thrown away.
They're gone.
Go buy sweet cakes for yourself.
Just buy whatever you want,
and eat whatever you want!
We like different food.
Neither of us should make a compromise.
But I do have a request.
if you didn't want to have noodles,
you should've let me know earlier,
so that I wouldn't have bothered to
order two bowls of noodles and wasted them!
I...
Yuanzhong,
are you asleep?
May I come in?
If you don't say anything,
I'll take it as a yes.
Yuanzhong,
I didn't have dinner.
I felt too hungry to fall asleep.
So,
I bought two bowls of noodles.
Can you get up and eat them
with me?
Are you asleep?
Today, Mr. Xu in Qiju Pavilion
said an important person
was impressed by my craft skills,
so he wanted to meet me.
But all I was thinking at that time
was that I must come back to have dinner with you.
So I declined to meet with that person.
Later, on my way back,
I met a child.
He gave me a lantern,
saying that it would
lead me
to a gentleman who was longing to see me.
I thought that was you,
so I went for the meeting.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know you would
wait for me for so long.
I've finished eating.
I should probably go.
If you feel hungry,
please get up and have a bite.
If you let the noodles sit here for too long,
they will stick together and taste bad.
Grand Elder, we're out of Blood Pills.
Maybe you'll feel better with this ginseng tea.
Without Blood Pills,
whatever I drink won't make a difference.
How about...
How about
we beg the High Priest?
He might agree, right?
Mr. Qi!
Isn't he Mr. Qi?
Mr. Qi,
word has it in the city
that you're preparing a new work.
Is it true?
Mr. Qi,
you said you were creating
a new work half a year ago.
We have waited
for so long.
When can we
feast our eyes on your new work?
Yeah!
When can we feast our eyes on it?
Mr. Qi,
could you tell us something
about your new work?
Yes! Please, tell us about it.
Ladies and gentlemen,
when my new work is ready,
I will certainly let you know.
However, for now,
please don't block the road.
After all, I don't own
the streets of Yandu City.
If you keep chasing
after me like this,
I'm afraid it will
bring me a bad reputation.
Mr. Zhao.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Stop now.
High Priest Yuanzhong,
what a lovely surprise to see you here.
I was looking everywhere for you.
What do you want?
Let's talk inside.
High Priest,
you usually eat here, don't you?
Nobody invited you to come.
Sir,
may I take your order?
Bring me
all the signature dishes
of your restaurant.
I'm sorry.
We only serve noodles,
and nothing else.
Nothing else?
Then go out and buy some.
Go to Dengyun House.
They know what I like to eat.
Plus,
the bill will be paid by this gentleman.
That's it. Just go.
Do as I say.
Okay.
You didn't order the sweet and sour crispy pork for me!
Why are you glaring at me?
You deserve to pay for this meal.
I searched all the hotels,
but I couldn't find you.
Where are you staying?
Cut to the chase.
You know what?
A person's life
is like a long journey.
One may have an idea when his or her journey starts.
But on the way,
he or she might have a change of mind.
Nonetheless,
in any case,
the beautiful scenery remains constant.
You and I are just passersby on her journey.
Do you understand?
No, I don't.
From the bottom of my heart,
I don't think you two are suitable for each other.
There's no way she would be into
someone like you instead of me.
But she still fell for you.
What exactly are you trying to say?
Nothing.
Never mind.
I said that in your best interest.
This is the Divine Left Hand, isn't it?
I've heard it's quite powerful.
Show me what it's capable of.
Are you sure you want to see that?
Forget it.
Don't show me.
High Priest Yuanzhong,
I wish you happiness.
Me?
Yes.
You'll live a long life.
It's a shame I can't enjoy the food now.
Goodbye.
These medicines can improve your energy.
I also bought some snacks
for you and Xue.
Here you are.
Why are you doing all this?
I'd love to help those in need and do a good deed every day.
I know.
Your nature isn't essentially bad.
Otherwise, those
who have tried to catch you along your way
would have died long ago.
I have been deprived of my magic source,
so I couldn't beat them down.
Even though you've lost your magic source,
as a War Demon,
you would barely
break a sweat to kill them.
Some people and some things
are not as simple as they appear.
If you just enjoy being kind and generous,
then please keep your eyes open.
Otherwise,
you might get hurt by someone one day.
I don't understand what you're saying.
The High Priest of the Youhu Clan
has probably turned into a demon.
Look at the sea.
It's dark and gloom.
with raging storms and snow.
Your sea of consciousness is so dark.
It barely has any difference from
the inner world of us demons.
It's your fate to grow into a demon.
Join us now.
Become one with me.
Be a member of the demon clan!
That night,
I overheard the conversation
between them and Li Chaoyang.
Yuanzhong's eyes
are like those of a demon.
Li Chaoyang wouldn't have said those words without reason.
You're with Yuanzhong all the time.
Please do stay alert.
[Liujiao Palace]
♫Too many old dreams♫
♫Where did the snow fall to?♫
Catching a glimpse of Chizhou to the east of Tanlu Pavilion,
♫Going to face a catastrophe♫
I was delighted.
We crossed Di River and Wan Creek.
♫No one is irrelevant♫
After passing through some lonely lands,
we drank sweet wine aplenty.
Everyone enjoyed the party.
♫A slight ripple in my gaze♫
There was a good spread of delicious and precious food.
♫Who knows the warmth and cold of my fleeting life?♫
Countless jugs of wine were provided.
Laying on ice, we drank happily; watching the snow, we sang pleasantly.
♫If staying together is difficult, it's not worth it♫
♫I'll return what's left of my life♫
On a clear night,
an unusual phenomenon appeared.
♫Falling into the mortal world♫
♫Wandering through the clouds and rivers♫
Across the black sky,
a beam of five-colored light showed up.
♫Being by your side is like finding the shore♫
It was like a dragon, or a snake.
♫If between oaths♫
The whole space was lit up.
It didn't go away until half a month later.
♫I hold onto the longing for just one more glance♫
♫Unwilling to bid farewell for good♫
♫Tears grow cold in a single cup♫
Yuanzhong,
this world is really big.
♫Longing fades in half♫
The feuds between Youhu Clan
♫Like flowers in a mirror, or the moon in the water♫
and the War Demons aren't the only thing that exists.
You should go out, see the world,
♫A thousand years of long nights, yearning from dawn to dusk♫
and spend some joyful days.
You want to read it too?
Then let's read it together.
♫A slight ripple in my gaze♫
Catching a glimpse of Chizhou to the east of Tanlu Pavilion,
♫Who knows the warmth and cold of my fleeting life?♫
I was delighted.
♫If staying together is difficult, it's not worth it♫
♫I'll return what's left of my life♫
♫Falling into the mortal world♫
♫Wandering through the clouds and rivers♫
♫Being by your side is like finding the shore♫
♫The moon falls by the riverbank♫
♫The light finally dims♫
♫How can my heart be at ease?♫
What are you doing?
♫Tears grow cold in a single cup♫
♫Longing fades in half♫
♫Like flowers in a mirror, or the moon in the water♫
Nothing.
I'm just checking on Xiu.
♫The lonely guest can't sleep, destiny can't be undone; speechless♫
The mushrooms look fresh.
Leave the water till later.
Let the soup be cooked for longer,
so the taste can be stronger.
Where have you been today?
I...
I went to Qiju Pavilion.
What for?
To repair five-wheel fans.
Well...
Mr. Xu
asked me to repair them.
I didn't ask who told you to fix them.
You went to Qiju Pavilion
must be because Mr. Xu
asked you for a favor.
That said,
weren't those fans
just fixed a few days ago?
There are many five-wheel fans.
Dozens of them.
The repair isn't done yet.
Do you remember Xue?
Xue?
Xue from the tower ship.
I mean that handmaiden.
The chubby one,
with a lovely smile.
After she got off the tower ship,
she used her commission to rent a small house.
Now she's staying
near the entrance of Daozi Street.
I was wondering
why she wouldn't go home.
Maybe she just feels unpleasant
to live with her brother and sister-in-law.
And I...
I want to ask you something.
What is it?
At the end of your sea of consciousness,
which is the ninth layer of your dream,
what exactly does it contain?
You want to know that?
Yes, I do.
I'll tell you later.
Qian Lin,
I really don't know
where Tanyin lives.
You can keep following me,
but I still don't know where she lives.
I'm really worried about her.
What are you worried about?
She is with the High Priest
of Youhu Clan now.
The High Priest is a god.
Nobody can hurt her.
A god?
Who knows which he really is,
a god or a demon?
The weather is good.
It's time to come out and enjoy the sunshine.
Indeed.
There is a letter from Elder Xinyao,
inquiring about your condition.
Just tell her
I am all fine.
It turns out that the people
in Fangwai Mountain also care about Mr. Tanghua.
Mr. Tanghua.
Greetings, Young City Lord.
You're looking much better now.
I'm relieved.
Today, I specially brought
some seasonal fruits
to you.
These are some local specialties
of Yandu City.
We do have some fruits
that we usually send to Fangwai Mountain as tributes.
But they're not as good as the freshly picked fruits.
Thank you, Young City Lord.
Are you satisfied with the servants?
If you need anything or have a complaint,
please do let me know.
Thank you for being such a nice host.
Everything is fine here.
Mr. Tanghua, you came from afar.
It has been long since you left home.
I believe there are many affairs to
be dealt with in Fangwai Mountain.
It's no wonder that Immortal Elder Xinyao
often sends her regards to you.
Elder Xinyao is kind.
She cares about everyone in the clan,
not just me.
But you're still different.
You are the commander of
the War Division in Youhu Clan.
You hold a high ranking and strong power in the clan.
I bet
they need to ask your advice
about numerous affairs
on a daily basis.
I think I hardly handle as many
issues as you do, Young City Lord.
The old city lord is in seclusion now.
I believe you must be attending to
all the affairs in Yandu City right now,
aren't you, Young City Lord?
Now that I'm in this position,
I have to fulfill my duties.
The War Demons have reappeared.
Next, the War Division of Youhu Clan
will absolutely be busy working
and making plans.
It's true that your health
has improved,
but riding a horse back home
to handle affairs
must be inconvenient to you.
So a few days ago,
I already had my servants
prepare a cozy carriage
for your use.
Young City Lord, it's very considerate of you.
Jiuguang,
wash the fruits
brought by Young City Lord,
and get us a pot of tea.
I've been here for days,
yet you and I haven't had a nice talk.
That's true.
Young City Lord.
Mr. Tanghua,
it's time you took medicine.
As Young Mistress Zhi Dai said,
you can't drink tea before taking medicine.
Would you come back inside?
I nearly forgot it.
Young City Lord, I'm sorry I have to go.
No problem.
Youhu Clan
just won't leave us alone.
He can't keep spying on us for much longer.
The commander of Youhu Clan's War Division
can't stay forever in Yandu City, right?
The young city lord
seems to be up to something.
Keep an eye on him.
I need to know
what Zhi Yue is planning.
I heard that the people in Yandu City
had prepared a long time for this lantern show.
Everyone has brought out
all the pretty lanterns they have.
So beautiful.
Humans are always gifted
at things like this.
It didn't sound like a compliment.
But it was, genuinely.
I do appreciate a lot of things
created by humans.
Sir,
here's a lantern for you.
May good fortune befall you.
Thank you.
Such an auspicious omen.
Just like the Lucky Eggs you created.
Here you are.
You have a beautiful smile now.
Several days ago,
you looked preoccupied.
There are much more
patrol guards today than before.
That's for sure.
This is a big event.
They are deployed to ward off villains.
When you traveled around
as the Mute Lady of Wu Mountain,
did you encounter anyone evil?
How do you define "evil"?
Those who are born evil, do or say evil things
or harbor evil thoughts
are evil.
Of course I did.
What happened then?
What did you do?
I would try to reason with them.
What if you couldn't get through to them?
In that case,
I would use
the Mute Lady of Wu Mountain's own way.
The Mute Lady of Wu Mountain
is regarded as a god by the people of the Eastern Wilderness.
She would help anyone.
It's hard to imagine she would have a way to deal with evil people.
A Bodhisattva lowered eyebrows and a Vajra's angry glare
both represent mercy.
If one knows something is evil
but still indulges it,
then this person is doing evil.
Right.
However,
what if an evil person is wronged?
Only what one does can define who he is.
Nobody is perfect if judged by their thoughts.
For those who harbor evil intentions or speak evil things,
we cannot ignore
how they have been wronged.
For those who are born evil or do evil deeds,
we should look at
the results of their doings.
It sounds like there are certain standards.
But
who set up those standards?
Can you represent fairness and justice?
No, I cannot.
But the Six Realms work by their own rules.
Humans have their own laws.
Immortals have their own rules.
If someone goes against the order and rules,
disregards all the living beings，
aims to become a demon and disturbs the harmony,
this person will be punished by heavenly laws.
As many reasons as this person may have,
he or she must pay a price
for what he or she has done.